Humanity
has been bestowed [music] with great
gifts. Perhaps greatest of all is our
imagination because [music] ultimately
it's our imaginations that enable us to
shape the world around us. The most
obvious examples [music] of that are the
great buildings and architecture all
around us. But which works [music] of
architecture should we see during our
lifetimes? Find out in top 10. The art
of architecture.
Although the European tradition of opera
goes back at least to early 1600s,
the first purpose-built opera houses
were only built towards the end of the
19th century. Before that, operas were
performed in traditional theaters or
other kinds of arena. Each of the 10
buildings in our top 10 is a wonder of
stage technology as well as a
masterpiece of modern or historic
architecture which fundamentally
enriches the city in which it was built.
Lascala, Milan, Italy.
Milan, Italy is where you will find
arguably the most renowned opera house
in the world. For more than 200 years,
it has been home to three celebrated
theatrical companies, the chorus, the
ballet, and the orchestra.
The previous theater housed in a wing of
the Royal Palace of Milan was destroyed
by a fire which broke out following a
carnival gala in 1776.
When the smoke had cleared, some wealthy
Milanazy who own private boxes in the
original theater got together. They
wrote to the governor of Milan
requesting that a new theater be built.
A splendid new theater at that.
The architect Jeppe Pierre Marini was
commissioned with its construction and
he had already [music] been contracted
to rebuild the ducal palace. The second
in two designs by Pier Marini was
approved in 1776 by Empress [music]
Maria Terresa herself.
It's been used to show something grand,
to show how good the country is. It's
part of our development, but in the end,
it's always for the people that are
going to be living in that architecture.
Byza decala was the site of the new
theater. It's ironic that the church of
Santa Maria Alaskala, which had given
both Opera House and Square their names,
was torn down to make way for the new
building.
The front facade may seem a little
austere,
but in that apparent simplicity lies the
secret of Lascala's imposing presence.
It is decorated by architectural
elements that all conform to an
established pattern.
A simple ground floor with a projecting
portico. A lavish first floor above it
adorned by rectangular and half columns
topped with decorations. And at the top
just a simple half story.
The triangular pediment in the center is
adorned with a sculpture depicting the
chariot of the sun being pursued by
night.
The opera house was designed for 3,000
spectators with building expenses part
funded by the sale of private [music]
boxes.
Commoners could buy a ticket for the
main floor where they had to stand to
watch the performance. For the least
welloff, there was a peanut gallery
whose occupants were considered the most
passionate spectators.
Even today, they have been known to boo
an actor offstage during a performance,
thus forcing them to be hastily
replaced.
The atmosphere at Lascala could seem
rather strange even in the 19th century.
Mary Shelley, author of the novel
Frankenstein, noted that on her visit to
Lascala, it had been almost impossible
to hear the music because the spectators
had been so loud, arranging meetings,
even making deals. This jolly mood often
leaked out to the foyer where a casino
had been set up for an opera house. It
was a racy kind of a place.
Lascala opened with a production of
Antonio Salieri's Europa Reconnisc.
But it is an Italian composer Joeppi Vi
who was most associated with Lascala.
Bulchoy Theater, Moscow, Russia.
Which came first, the performers or the
theater? In the case of Moscow State
Academic Grand Theater, the performers.
What is known popularly as the Bolshoy
Ballet was founded in 1776
after a decree was issued by Empress
Catherine the Great.
The company began by performing at the
Petrofski Theater until 185 when the
theater burned down. For a few short
years, they performed in the Arbat, a
wooden theater also destroyed by fires
set during Napoleon's occupation of
Moscow in 1812.
It would be several more years before
the opera and drama company could move
into a new building, one designed in the
style of monumental classicism.
The history of the Grand Theater
building really started in 1819
when a construction tender was announced
for the building.
Although it was won by a professor at
the Moscow Academy of Arts, his project
never saw the light of day. The governor
of Moscow, worried about high
construction costs, entrusted the
project to one, Joseph Boove.
The Russian Italian neocclassical
architect oversaw most of Moscow's
reconstruction after the fire of 1812
and was a safe pair of hands.
this very hard it must be to be an
architect because it takes so many years
when you plan it and you see it realized
in 1812 much of Moscow had been
decimated by Napoleon's incursion
including the fires which quote unquote
welcomed the grand army as they marched
into the
The destruction left behind ironically
an ideal building site on which Bo could
construct the brand new theater square
in the middle of which he situated the
impressive Bolshoy Theater. Its
construction began in 1820 and was
completed 5 years later.
Joseph Boove conceived the gracefully
simple yet monumental building as a
traditional precenium stage with a
horseshoe shaped auditorium for 2,000
spectators.
The orchestra pit located between the
auditorium and the stage was located in
a purpose-built basement. During
ballroom dances, it could be covered
with a sliding floor.
Joseph Bove had an innovative way to
deal with the theatrical rigging system
too.
Instead of housing it in the customary
tower and distorting the strict symmetry
of the building, he designed a low
superructure spanning the entire length
of the building.
The entrance portico with its columns
and a bronze statue of the Greek god
Apollo in a chariot drawn by four horses
is splendid.
The first ever performance was held on
June the 1st, 1825.
Less than 30 years later in 1853, a fire
destroyed the theater. The only parts
left standing were the outer walls and
part of the portico. The reconstruction
of the theater was carried out at an
incredibly fast pace so that on August
the 20th, 1856, the birthday of Zar
Alexander II, the theater was
inaugurated.
The roof, the pillars and walls were now
all fitted with a richly decorated
facade.
Reconstruction brought about a number of
renovations, too. There was an increase
in the number of seats though the
auditorium was still dominated by the
so-called Zars Lodge which was decorated
with gold stucco.
This symbol of imperial privilege was
destroyed by the communists after the
revolution of 1917.
The original glamour of the dilapidated
Bolshoy Theater was brought back to life
by the 2011 refurbishment at a cost of a
mere 21 billion rubles.
Pelle Gier, Paris, France.
The first ever opera house to be built
in Paris today bears the name Opera Gier
in honor of its architect Sha Gier. It
is also a prototype of the kind of opera
house which emerged in the latter half
of the 19th century.
I think it's very good to have the
history there, especially in Europe
where a lot of history were torn down.
It was really only in the second half of
the 19th century that monumental public
buildings became an integral part of
modern European cities.
These cities were undergoing a radical
transformation from their origins as
medieval towns.
The redevelopment of Paris into a modern
city was a passion of the emperor
Napoleon III, a nephew of Napoleon
Bonapart.
One reason for building the opera house
was said to have been an attempted
assassination of Napoleon III in 1858
while he was on his way to the opera.
The bomb thrown by an Italian
revolutionary did not harm the emperor
but gave him the idea to build a new
opera house. The site was chosen by
prefect housemen who surprised everyone
with the competition to select the
architect anonymously. Over
170 architects applied, but the winning
project was by a young and virtually
unknown architect named Sha Gany.
He was under 40 years old, had only one
previous design come to completion, and
did not even have his own studio.
He set up shop in little more than a
garden shed and asked his classmates
from Echo Deose Arts, the school of fine
arts to help him.
Construction was due to be completed in
1867 in time for the International
Exposition, but straight away was beset
[music] with problems. The most serious
emerged as soon as the foundations were
dug. The issue was rising groundwater
from the river sane. The fire brigade
was called in to deal with it, pumping
it out continuously 24 hours a day. Gier
was forced to incorporate water
reservoirs into his design.
creating a sort of artificial lagoon.
Fascinatingly, it was the underwater
cellar and a later fatal accident
involving a falling chandelier which
gave writer Gaston Lero story ideas for
the Phantom of the Opera.
Visitors who set off to Paris in 1867
for the International Exposition
were only able to see the opera house
from the outside. It was to be another 8
years before its richly decorated
interiors were all completely finished.
The Neo Barack Opera House is made up of
several sections and their boundaries
are visible on the facade. Gier was
convinced the interior layout should be
reflected on the outside.
This way, distinct sections of the
building correspond directly to their
function.
The first section housing the foyer and
a number of salons is dominated by its
majestic looking corridors and
intricately decorated staircase.
The second section, the auditorium,
which can hold up to 2,000 people, is
capped off by a rounded dome in the
manner of Italian theaters. The final
section is the technical and
administrative wing, more functional in
design. The whole building is extended
on each side by pavilions which serve as
entrance halls for VIP spectators.
Garnier came under criticism for this as
the emperor's pavilion with access ramp
disrupted the building's symmetry. In
any case, Shal Gier created a building
synonymous with monumental architecture
in the 19th century.
Royal Albert Hall, London, Great
Britain.
In the unashamedly posh neighborhood of
Kensington in West London, you'll find
one of the world's most famous concert
halls. Amid royal residences, gardens,
museums, and luxury shopping streets,
[music]
this cathedral of art and science was
built between 1867 and 1871.
It was named after Queen Victoria's
consort Albert who was very keen to
promote the work of contemporary
classical composers.
In May 1851,
London was the site of the first World's
Fair, the Great Exhibition for which the
architect Joseph Paxton built the famous
Crystal Palace.
The exhibition was a huge success and
gave Prince Albert the idea to build a
quarter developed to art and culture.
Soon a large site in South Kensington
had been purchased and the project
dubbed Alberto Pollace was in part
financed from the profits of the great
exhibition.
No cultural quarter would be complete
without a concert hall. This one was
designed by the architects Captain
Francis Folk and Major General Henry
Scott. Both were officers in the Royal
Engineers, the British Army Corps.
They were clearly influenced by ancient
Greek amphitheaters and Roman arenas and
by the Renaissance.
But they were also inspired by the
German architect Gotfried Sea whose neo
renaissance buildings can still be
admired today in Dresdon, Zurich and
Vienna.
This oval building of red brick work has
four monumental entrances facing north,
south, east, and west. But apart from
certain stone elements such as the
pillars, arched windows and [music]
entrances, the only real decorative
element is the terra cotta freeze, which
runs in a band around the oval building
and depicts the triumph of arts and
sciences.
Above the freeze is a glass and rot iron
dome designed by engineer Roland Ordish
assembled in Manchester and then
transported to London. When the time
came for the supporting structure to be
removed, many fled the site thinking it
would collapse.
The Royal Albert Hall can accommodate
well over 5,000 spectators. They come
for the annual series of classical music
concerts called the Proms and for
performances throughout the year by the
big names in classical and popular
music.
And of course inside acoustic is when
people are clapping like this it's like
melody also I think it must be very good
acoustic.
Serge Rakmanov performed here. Richard
Vagnner conducted his great works and
Albert Einstein led a scientific
conference. Prince Albert's dream of a
place where art and science could meet
still holds true today.
Tiatro Colon Bunazeris Argentina.
Aside from its other attractions, the
Argentine capital can boast one of the
best opera houses in the world, the
Teatro Colon or Christopher Columbus
Theater, located in the very heart of
Buunazeris.
The first Columbus Theater was built in
the 1950s in Plaza del Mayo, where today
you'll find the Kaza Rosada, the
Argentine equivalent of the White House.
The initial opera house building could
host up to 2,500 people and served its
purpose until 1888
when it was demolished due to the new
building on Plaza del Mayo.
The first stone of the new Columbus
Theater was laid 2 years later. It was
intended that it would open its doors in
1892,
the 400th anniversary of Columbus's
discovery of America.
However, financial difficulties caused
more than 15 years delay. The original
theater was designed by the Italian
architect Francesco Tambborini, who
designed and remodeled many monumental
buildings in Buunazeris.
Tambborini died shortly after the
building works began, which were then
taken over by his partner, Victoriao
Mino, also an Italian.
In 1904, with the building still
unfinished, Mauo died too in a scandal.
He was allegedly shot dead by his wife's
lover.
Belgian architect Dormal was asked to
finish the project.
The European architect separately and
together created a building which
unsurprisingly comes across as very
European.
The final touches under Dormal's
supervision seem inspired by French
eclectic architecture.
Its horseshoes shaped main hall has a
vated ceiling with painted frescos by
French artist Marcel Jambon.
In 2008, the Colon Theater will be 100
years old. It has been a very busy
theater. Of course, this intensive use
has caused some damage. It needs to be
modernized in order to maintain its
unique character and also to provide
increased comfort for artists and the
audience.
Theatro Kon is a monumental building.
The auditorium with its boxes and
balconies arranged on three levels can
host over 2,000 people. The stage slopes
down towards the auditorium and is
equipped with a 20 m wide rotating disc
to enable quick scene changes.
The orchestra pit can accommodate
120 musicians.
In 1925, the theater acquired a
permanent orchestra, ballet, and choir,
and 12 years later, founded a performing
art school. Tiatro Kon is renowned
throughout the opera world for its
perfect acoustics of which, it is said
Luchiano Pavarotti himself was a fan.
Amphitheaters and arenas belong to a
tradition which goes back to antiquity.
The traditional precenium [music] stage
with a rectangular floor plan. This is
also a part of history. But in the last
100 years or so, new designs for opera
houses and concert halls began to
emerge, such as the fan-shaped stages or
indeed the vineyard style where the
stage is located in the middle of the
hall and the seats are arranged around
it. This arrangement was first employed
by architect Hans Shaun for the Berlin
philarmonic concert hall. Also, as
technology developed, architects began
to think more about the acoustic aspects
of their designs.
Palazzio de Bella's Arts, Mexico City,
Mexico.
The Palace of Fine Arts in the Mexican
capital is deceiving. It looks as if it
was built during [music] the peak of
historicism in the second half of the
19th century
when actually it was finished when the
general direction of European
architecture was set by Laabusier and
the artists of the Bow House Art School
in Desau
in the year 1900 due to the extension of
the May 5th boulevard in Mexico city.
The old National Theater building was
swept away. It was decided to replace it
with a building so splendid it could
become a source of national pride.
Plans for the eclectic building which
merges historicism and art nuvo were
drawn up by the Italian architect Adamo
Bori. The construction of the palace
dominated by its tower and dome began in
194.
The plan was to complete it within four
years, but due to the complexity of the
project, the 1910 revolution, the
ensuing economic crisis, and boy
returned to Europe held things up.
By the early 1920s, the unfinished
building with the massive steel skeleton
of its dome [music] still resembled one
huge construction site.
Things only started to look up in 1928
when Mexican architect Federico Mariscal
was put in charge of the project.
He picked up where Bari's plans left
off, but changed the interior style to
art deco, which seemed somehow a better
fit.
We need architects who are very
sensitive to the use of the place.
The 50 m plus high palace claded with
white marble from Kurara, Italy was
officially opened on November the 29th,
1934.
There are three main parts. The central
hall with exhibition space, a theater
hall with 1,800 seats, the necessary
technical facilities, and an office and
administrative section. Above the
auditorium hangs a huge ceiling made
from opal glass by the famous New York
studio Tiffany.
I think you can see quite fantastic
continuous line of of also change but
also based based on the kind of the art
it represents.
>> In the richly decorated interior there
are murals by prominent Mexican artists.
The most famous of whom are of course
Diego Rivera and Joseé Clemente Orosco.
The Palace of Fine Arts, which has been
on the UNESCO list of world heritage
site since 1987, is now the seat of
Mexican National Cultural Institutions
such as the Institute of Fine Arts, the
National Symphony Orchestra, Dance
Company, and Opera, as well as the
Museum of Architecture located in the
space below the dome.
Sydney Opera House, [music] Sydney,
Australia.
The extraordinary Sydney Opera House
designed by Danish architect Yorn Uten
captured the attention of the world. Its
origins go back to 1956 when the New
South Wales government announced an
international design competition. Some
233 projects were submitted.
What should have been euphoria for the
winning architect, however, soon became
a bit of a nightmare.
An opera house designed by a foreigner
was seen as an embarrassment to the
conservative opposition, the Liberal
Party, when they came to power in 1966.
They dismissed Utson from the project
and put local architects in charge. The
building was completed according to his
design, but Utson was shut out of the
construction process and so the
disgusted Danish architect left Sydney
never to return.
The Opera House is located on the harbor
close to the Royal Botanic Gardens and
of course the Sydney Harbor Bridge. It
rises up from a large platform evocative
of classical amphitheaters as well as
ancient Mayan architecture. Even before
it was chosen, Utson's design was
controversial.
And actually it was thrown away from the
competition. And then some in the jury
saw the sketch and uh here we have it.
This will be the the next Opra in
Sydney.
Orson also drew inspiration from nature.
Originally conceiving his masterpiece as
a set of seashells, their curves evoking
waves on the ocean. But this visually
pleasing solution proved a tough nut to
crack. Even for one of the leading
structural engineers of the day, O Arab,
another Dne, incidentally,
adaptations were made to the design,
such as making the ribs of the lower
shells from pre-cast reinforced
concrete.
In service of what might be called
architectural purity, Utson wanted all
the services and utilities to be located
underground. But after his dispute with
the New South Wales government, the
interiors were not constructed according
to Utson's plans.
Yet, despite all these problems, few
would deny that a visit to the opera
house is a one-ofa-kind aesthetic
experience.
And when you come into the opera,
it's wood, beautiful wood, but it's also
glass high up. So then you see the
people moving on the outside and then
you see people in almost like a
performance.
The project suffered lengthy delays
which unsurprisingly had a big impact on
the budget. Formally opened by Queen
Elizabeth II in 1973,
building costs exceeded the original
budget of 7 million Australian dollars,
more than 10 times. The finished opera
complex covers almost two hectares with
five concert halls, a recording studio,
restaurants, and exhibition space.
Concert hall audiences may also admire
the world's largest mechanical pipe
organ, which has over 10,000 pipes.
In 2007, just one year before his death,
Yorn Uten had the satisfaction of seeing
the Sydney Opera House listed as a
UNESCO World Heritage site.
Walt Disney Concert Hall, Los Angeles,
USA.
One of the newest major concert halls in
the US glitters even by the standards of
Tinsel Town. It's the Walt Disney
Concert Hall in Los Angeles, designed by
architect Frank Giri.
In 1991, Lillian Disney, widow of Walt
Disney, donated $50 million to get the
project up and running.
For the then 62year-old Frank Giri, it
was a return in a sense to his roots.
Giri had designed his first buildings in
California, especially in Santa Monica
and Los Angeles.
Those early designs followed a cheerful
post-modern style, but even his later
works have a certain playfulness. They
were also [music] user friendly
buildings.
If you have an agenda, you'll fail. So
you have to have a a a purpose and a
promise and a hope and a you bring your
talents whatever they are to the table
and you respond to the clients and their
needs.
When construction started on the Walt
Disney Concert Hall, Giri was already
designing buildings in France, Germany,
Spain, and the Czech Republic.
The turning point of his career was his
work on the Guggenheim Museum, Bil Bao,
in Spanish Basque country. Completed in
1997, the Bil Bao is probably Giri's
signature building. His deconstructivist
designs were made possible by utilizing
the latest technology, especially
computer programs.
All of his works stand out in the crowd.
For many years it was very popular to be
very integrated. You know you shouldn't
see what is art and what is the other
things. And then of course one gets a
little bit fed up with that. So now I
feel it's getting more vivid. One can
really make special thing that stands
out but at the same time talks with the
building. For example,
>> in 2001, Giri started Giri Technologies,
which has been at the forefront of
developing computer software for
building design ever since. With the
Walt Disney Concert Hall, Giri was able
to repeat the success of his work in
Spain, covering the facade with a
stainless steel skin.
Most of it was given a matte finish, but
the founders's room and children's
amphitheater were both covered with
highly polished panels.
These, however, reflected so much
sunlight that nearby pavements and
buildings started to overheat with the
increased risk of traffic accidents
[music] due to the blinding glare.
Giri's company developed a computer
program to analyze the glare.
Eventually, they were able to eliminate
the glare by lightly sanding the
offending panels.
But what about inside? Well, all the
experts agree the acoustics of the
auditorium at Disney are of the highest
level. Designed as they were by Tokyo
based studio Nagata Acoustics, their
sound designs for concert halls with a
vineyard seating plan is reputedly
second to none.
None of this came cheap, however. By the
time of the opening ceremony in 2003,
the budget had soared to $274 million
US. City Hall and private sponsors
contributed to this figure, and the
Disney family and Walt Disney Company
put in more than $100 million. But Los
Angeles gained a concert hall of world
renown. And Frank Giri [music]
showed yet again why he is one of the
leading architects of our time. Immune
to popular trends and not prepared to
sacrifice style [music] at any cost.
Copenhagen Opera House, Copenhagen,
Denmark.
The Royal Opera House in Copenhagen is
located on the seashore on Dohorn,
meaning Dock Island.
It is just opposite the racoo palaces of
Amelianborg,
the residence of the Danish royal
family.
This stunningly impressive opera house
was designed by the Danish architect
Henning Len and sponsored by the Molar
family who donated it to the nation. The
super rich shipping family sunk $500
million US into the project. So far so
good except its construction became a
source of heated debate.
>> They were not happy with it and the
architect who made it didn't want to
sign it in the ant. So I think that had
been quite a lot of discussion and so it
lost the energy the opera house.
There were some who considered it a
Trojan horse rather than an act of
philanthropy, probably because of fears
of high operation costs and the
sponsor's unwillingness to compromise on
any detail.
They insisted on the best materials and
implementation, which meant that
everything had to be tested during
construction. This was not to the liking
of the architect. Yet the building was
completed in 2005,
having taken just four years to build.
And so Copenhagen gained not only a
remarkable architectural work, but an
opera house with several cuttingedge
features.
The front of the huge building is not
unlike the bridge of a big container
ship. Perhaps one from the Molar
family's highly successful shipping
company, MEK. Traditional material,
principally stone, is much in evidence.
The limestone cladding both suits and
contrasts with a dynamic central section
of the front facade.
This was designed by a convex glazed
wall assembled from rectangular panels
laid sideways.
Behind this transparent surface is the
central foyer which provides splendid
views of the Danish capital as well as
the main auditorium.
Len designed the interior in a similar
manner to the exterior. Apart from
steel, glass and polished wood, the
predominating material is in this case
Sicilian marble, it is enhanced by
numerous works of art by leading artists
from Scandinavia and across the world.
Among these is the unusual main curtain
designed by Pere and who used an optical
illusion to create a three-dimensional
effect.
The illusion is so complete that it
deceives not only the naked eye but also
the lenses of cameras which are
virtually unable to capture the unusual
effect.
The opera house has one principal
auditorium with one main stage but five
other stages are joined which means that
scenery can be moved simply and quickly
to the main stage during a performance.
This allows the opera producers to use
six main sets for any one performance.
The building's 1,000 rooms have a total
floor space of 41,000 square m, and the
main auditorium can seat as many as
1,700 people, depending on the size of
the orchestra. On that note, part of the
orchestra pit is located underground.
Arguably the only blemish on the
otherwise completely unique opera house
which is at least for now the most
expensive in the world.
The National Center for the Performing
Arts, Beijing, China.
[music]
The National Center for the Performing
Arts or the NCPA is located in the heart
of old Beijing. It is close to the great
hall of the people, Tanaman Square and
the ancient forbidden city. The decision
to build the Grand National Theater in a
place of such historical and symbolic
importance says a lot about the high
expectations for the institution.
[music] The NCPA was designed by French
architect Paul with construction
beginning in December 2001. Paul
believed that while there is value in
traditional Chinese architecture,
Beijing must also present the best and
brightest in modern architecture.
His design is certainly contemporary and
yet with its large open spaces, water
and trees was designed to complement the
red walls of ancient buildings and the
great hall of the people to blend with
its surroundings and not overpower them.
NCPA officially opened in December 2007
and as cuttingedge architecture in
Beijing has yet to be surpassed.
I think that the people of Beijing are
very curious about it. I think they want
to come into this building that they've
seen from the outside for weeks, even
years now. They want to come in and have
a look.
The oval-shaped titanium and glass shell
encloses an opera house, a concert hall,
two theaters, and several public spaces.
Surrounded by green lawns and gardens,
and [music] an artificial lake, it is
seen as a cultural island in the middle
of the bustling Chinese capital.
The huge silvery construction has a
total area over 215,000
square meters
with an underground car park alone of
more than 45,000
m. Note the theatrical motive of its
exterior. The outer titanium shell is
broken by a glass curtain suggestive of
a stage curtain going up.
Around the lake is a green belt
conferring a sense of serenity amid the
hustle and bustle of a modern city and
anchoring the NCPA in a tranquil green
garden.
Guests only arrive in the building after
walking through a hallway that goes
underneath the lake. quite a talking
point during the 2008 Olympic Games.
The Olympic performance season will on
the other hand intensify the atmosphere
of the Olympic Games and on the other
hand it will provide friends and
visitors from all over the world a
perfect site for them to enjoy arts.
Oh, you for the Tor.
It is certainly busy these days as the
Center for the Arts. The Opera House is
the cent's largest venue, hosting
elaborate productions, while the concert
hall hosts symphony orchestras and
national music performances. The
multifunctional theater consists of two
lifting platforms that can be elevated
as needed.
There are also a number of public spaces
designed to amaze and stimulate jointly
known as the fifth space. They include
the underwater corridor, the Olive Hall,
an exhibition gallery, a resource
center, terrace lounge, souvenir shops
and cafes.
The five buildings you have seen in the
second part of this program are at the
very pinnacle of contemporary
architectural design. Some of them have
been constructed in a relatively short
time while others took several years to
finish. However, they all represent the
very best of the best and have without
exception brought great cultural riches
to their respective cities.
>> [music]
[music]